463 AD. A nation in need of a legend.
Arthur & Merlin: Knights of Camelot is a adventure,
history, action film directed by Giles Alderson.
King Arthur returns home after fighting the Roman Empire.
His illegitimate son has corrupted the throne of Camelot and King Arthur must reunite with the
wizard Merlin and the Knights of the Round Table to fight to get back his crown.
Arthur, played by Richard Short.
The Beast, played by Joe Egan.
Lucan, played by Ronan Summers.
Tabitha, played by Olivia Bernstone.
Mathilde, played by Georgia Curtis.
Alexander, played by Charlie Hiett.
Camelot is a legendary castle and court associated with King Arthur.
Absent in the early Arthurian material, Camelot first appeared in 12th-century French romances and, since the Lancelot-Grail
cycle, eventually came to be described as the fantastic capital of Arthur's realm and a symbol of the Arthurian world.
Medieval texts locate it somewhere in Great Britain and sometimes associate it with
real cities, though more usually its precise location is not revealed.
Most scholars regard it as being entirely fictional, its unspecified
geography being perfect for chivalric romance writers.
Nevertheless, arguments about the location of the "real Camelot" have occurred since the
15th century and continue today in popular works and for tourism purposes.
The film explores themes of camelot, knight, king arthur, 5th century.